The Two Mangekyo
Zetsu… How long are you going
to cling to Obito?
(マダラ)ゼツ… いつまで オビトに
へばりついている？
(ゼツ)すみません ですが コイツらから
九尾の半身も奪っておきました。
Sorry…
But that allowed me to steal Nine Tails'
other half from these guys.
(マダラ)よし！
左目とあわせて持ってこい。
Good. Now bring it,
and my left eye, to me.
《ミナト : 仙人の力を感じる
これは オビトのときよりも更に…》
I sense Sage Power…
And it's much stronger than
what Obito possessed.
(我愛羅)やはり 四代目の九尾は
あの黒いヤツの中か…。
So the Fourth Hokage's Nine Tails
is inside that black thing!
Madara?!
(カカシ)マダラ どうやって六道の力を？
How did he get Six Paths' power?
Since Lord Madara is here,
you can't do anything to me…
マダラ様がいるかぎり
コイツから離れても→
お前らは
俺になんにもできはしない。
even if I separate myself
from Obito.
うっ!?
Now, Kakashi!
いくぞ カカシ！
うっ！ うぅ…。
(オビト)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
Why you—!
キサマ まだ…。
You're still—!
まだだ… アンタに話がある。 マダラ。
Not yet…
I need to
ask you something, Madara.
We need the Nine Tails inside
that thing for Naruto.
ナルトには ヤツの中の九尾が必要だ。
失敗はできない。
We cannot afford to miss.
ここぞというときでなければダメだ。
We have to wait for
the right moment.
アンタにとって 俺はなんだ？
Just what am I…to you?
(マダラ)フフフ…。
You're kidding, right?
冗談はよせ。
What kind of a stupid question is that,
at this point in time?
今更 くだらないことを聞くな。
お前は 俺にとって
他でもない→
You are only one thing to me…
マダラだ。
You are Madara.
Now go…
《マダラ : さあ 動け
俺が復活するまでの間→
Until the time when
I am revived…
お前が うちはマダラだ》
You shall be Madara Uchiha.
この世界を否定する存在が マダラだ。
Madara is he who rejects the world.
その思想を胸に行動し→
All who hold that in their heart…
and strive toward achieving
the Infinite Tsukuyomi are Madara.
無限月読の計画を狙う者は→
すべて マダラでしかない。
それは…。
That…
それは俺の道でもあった。
That was once my path too.
俺が眠りにつき帰るまでの間→
I left you in charge of everything…
お前に すべてを任せ→
And let you walk in my shoes,
while I slept, waiting to return.
俺の先を歩かせてやったのだ。
それは俺が示してやった道だ。
It's the path I guided you towards.
お前は目的達成のために→
You were supposed to live out
your life as Madara
マダラとして
天寿を全うするはずだった。
in order to achieve our goal.
この世界を救った救世主としてな。
As the savior who rescued this world.
六道仙人が示した この世界は→
This world laid out by
the Sage of the Six Paths…
失敗した。
has failed.
いいか。
Now listen…
六道の広めたチャクラとは→
The chakra dispersed by
the Six Paths was originally…
本来 繋ぐ力のことだ。
meant to be a linking power.
人と人の精神エネルギーを繋ぎ→
The mental energies of people
would connect and feelings
言葉なくとも
互いの心を理解し合い→
would be understood without
the need for words…
人々の安定を願うもの。
That would lead to peace and stability.
その力を忍宗として説き→
NINSHU
The one who preached this
as Ninshu, the Ninja Creed
人々に伝え導こうとしたのが
六道仙人だ。
and sought to guide the people,
was the Sage of the Six Paths.
だが人々は いつしか
互いの心を繋げるためではなく→
However…
But before long, people used chakra
not to connect with others
but only to link the mental and
physical energies within themselves.
己の中の精神エネルギーと→
身体エネルギーを繋ぐために
チャクラを使った。
己のチャクラを大きく練り上げ
増幅する方法で。
Through a method of infusing one's
own chakra and increasing it multifold…
武力となる忍術へと
チャクラを変換するためにな。
they changed chakra into ninjutsu
that could be used as weapons in battle.
皮肉にも六道の母 カグヤが→
Ironically reverting to the way
Six Paths' mother, Kaguya,
武力として チャクラを使用した道に
戻ったわけだ。
had originally used chakra.
(サクラ)いったい
何の話をしてるの？ コイツ。
Just what the hell is
he talking about?!
我愛羅。
わかっている。
Gaara…
I know.
六道仙人の行いは
人の矛盾を助長したにすぎん。
All the Sage of the Six Paths did was
to further the human paradox.
そして たとえ
心と 心を繋げたところで→
And even if bonds were established…
わかり合えないのが
わかるだけだったのだ。
All they learned was that
true understanding was not possible.
どちらにしろ
チャクラは 争いを生み→
In any case, chakra only gives rise
to conflict and false hope.
まやかしの希望を生むだけだった。
俺も お前たちも
平和を追い求めるのと同時に→
We all know the reality all too well…
Even as we seek peace,
we seek war.
争いを求めてきた現実がある。
この現実は
チャクラという力によって→
And this reality compels
infinite suffering
through the power known as chakra.
無限の苦しみを強いられている。
力があるから 争いを望み→
Power leads to the desire for war.
力がないから すべてを失う。
And the lack of power leads
to losing everything.
俺は それを乗り越えた
新たな世界をつくる。
I will build a new world
that overcomes that!
無限月読により→
Through the Infinite Tsukuyomi,
いまわしき チャクラなき
夢の世界をつくるのだ。
I will create a dream world
without any abominable chakra!
最後にして 最強のチャクラを持つ
この俺が導く。
I, who possess the most
powerful chakra, shall lead it!
そして お前は 俺そのものだ。
オビトではない。
And you are not Obito,
but me…Madara himself.
Obito Uchiha with his Uchiha Chakra,
challenged Kakashi Hatake,
(マダラ)うちはオビトは
うちはのチャクラがあるがゆえに→
はたけカカシに挑戦し 火影を望み→
desired the title of Hokage,
and yearned for Rin Nohara!
のはらリンを望んだ。
だが その力が
まやかしだったがために→
But because his power was false,
he ended up losing everything!
そのすべてを失ったのだ。
ここは 地獄だ。 忘れたのか!?
This is hell!
Have you forgotten?!
こっちへ来い。
Come over here.
来い。 そう マダラよ。
Yes, come, Madara!
今日から お前が救世主だ。
From this day forth,
you are a savior.
You are still the savior, even now.
今でも お前は 救世主のはずだ。
砂漠波！
Sand Wave!
神威！
Kamui!
仙術！
Sage Jutsu!
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
うおっ…。
そ… そんな ３人の攻撃が。
No way…
Their combined attack…
さあ…。
Now…
キサマ…。
You damned…
何のマネだ!?
What are you doing?!
No…
((オビト : いや…
俺のやっていることは→
What I'm doing is no different
than a Hokage's actions.
火影と何ら変わらない。
それ以上だ。
In fact, it's greater.
平和を実現できるのだからな。
Because I can truly
bring about peace.
険しい道だと わかっていて
歩くことはない。
There's no need to voluntarily
walk down a path
you know to be dangerous.
仲間の死体をまたぐだけだ。
You'll have to step over
the corpses of your friends.
それは俺が示してやった道だ。
It's the path I guided you to.
(ナルト)俺が知りてえのは
楽な道のりじゃねえ。
I don't want to know the easy path.
お前に すべてを任せ
俺の先を歩かせてやったのだ。
I left you in charge of everything…
And let you walk in my shoes…
火影ってのは 痛ぇのガマンして→
The Hokage is the one who
walks ahead of everyone else,
(みんなの前を
歩いているヤツのことだ))
who endures the pain.
人を導く者は 己の死体を
またがれることがあっても→
One who leads others…
is one who never steps
over his friends' corpses…
仲間の死体を
またいだりはしないらしい。
even if his own ends up
being stepped on.
なら それを確かめるために
まず お前が死体にならねばな。
Then in order to confirm that,
you'll have to become a corpse.
(オビト)俺はもう
アンタにまたがれることもない。
You won't be
stepping on me anymore.
己の名を騙らせ
他人にすべてを任せることは→
I realize now that letting someone
handle everything in your name
仲間に託すこととは違うと
今なら わかる。
isn't the same as truly
entrusting them with the task.
(オビト)俺は アンタじゃない。
I am not you.
((リン : 頑張れオビト。
Go for it, Obito!
火影になって かっこよく
世界を救うとこ 見せてね！
Become the Hokage
and save the world!
(それも 約束だよ！))
That's a promise too!
今の俺は 火影を語りたかった
うちはオビトだ！
The current me…
is the one who wanted
to be Hokage…Obito Uchiha!
Obito…
オビト…。
Obito…You've finally found yourself!
《オビト… お前やっと自分を…》
すり抜ける。
お前 本来の右目の力か。
I passed through you.
That's your original right eye's power.
俺から尾獣を奪い
弱体化を狙っているのか？
Are you trying to weaken me
by taking away the Tailed Beasts?
Do you think you can
challenge me and win?!
俺と取り合って
勝てると思っているとはな。
So weak…
弱いな。 一尾と八尾を
ほんの少し引きちぎった程度とは。
Is that all? You only tore off
a mere sliver of the One and Eight Tails?
カカシ！ ナルトを時空間へ運べ！
Kakashi!
Take Naruto into the Time-Space!
《オビトは あっちで
九尾を渡すつもりなのか？
Obito plans to hand him
the Nine Tails there!
Kamui!
神威！》
(サクラ)うわっ！
《神威！》
Kamui!
I know that when you teleport
your body materializes…
《自ら飛ぶときに
体が実体化するのは知っている》
《うかつに時空間に
飛ぼうとすれば→
If I try to teleport carelessly,
he'll come after me.
その隙を狙われる。
空間移動スピードが遅すぎる》
My teleportation speed is too slow.
一度 仙人化しただけはある。
Since he'd been in Sage mode once,
he was able to steal some
Sage Power from me too…
ほんの少しだが 俺から
その力まで吸い取ったか。
《マダラ… アイツは
いつでも私を殺せた。
Madara…
could have killed me at any time…
あまりの恐怖で
息をするのも忘れてた。
I was so scared I forgot to breathe!
アイツは… アイツだけは次元が違う》
Of all the people,
he's in a different class!
All right, I transported Naruto.
(カカシ)ナルトは運んだ。
All that's left is for you
to teleport yourself there
あとは お前が向こうへ飛べば
ナルトは助かるってことだな？
and Naruto will be saved, right, Obito?
(カカシ)オビト。
フン… まったく。
Damn it.
お前は いつも上から目線で→
You always talk down to me…
And act so superior…
Just like old times.
偉そうなことばかり言ってやがる。
昔から そうだ。
((オビト。
Obito!
Rin is here to pick you up.
リンちゃんが迎えにきたぞよ。
(オビト)ごめん ごめん リン！
Sorry, sorry, Rin!
早く ひ孫の顔が
見たいのう オビトよ。
I can't wait to see
my great-grandchild's face, Obito.
(オビト)ばあちゃん
俺 まだ５つだぞ？
Grandma, I'm only five years old.
早く 早く！ 始まっちゃうよ！
Come on, hurry,
it's going to start!
YOUTH NINJUTSU COMPETITION
お～っ！ これが賞品のクナイか！
Wow! This is the kunai prize!
かっこいいね！
It's so cool!
Okay, thank you very much!
はい どうも
ありがとうございました。
さて 次は どんな忍術かな？
I wonder what kind of
ninjutsu is next?
ヘヘッ このメンツなら
優勝いただきだぜ。
If these are the opponents,
this is going to be a piece of cake.
Number seven, Obito Uchiha!
７番 うちはオビト君！
That's me!
俺だ！
Go for it, Obito!
頑張れ オビト！
What are you going
to show us, Obito?
オビト君は
何をやってくれるのかな？
俺は火遁 豪火球の術をやるぜ。
おお すごいね！
I'm going to be doing
the Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Wow, impressive!
それじゃ よろしく。
いくぜ!!
All right, let's get right to it!
Here I go!
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
６点 ７点 ７点。
お～っ いい数字が出ました。
Six points! Seven points!
Seven points!
These are great numbers!
Obito Uchiha is in
the lead right now!
うちはオビト君が
ここまでのトップです！
That was great, Obito!
すごいね オビト！
ヘヘッ 今日は
ちょっと調子悪かったけど→
I wasn't in top form today,
but I think it's a sure win for me.
これなら
俺の優勝は間違いねえぜ！
All right, here's our final challenger!
それじゃ
最後の挑戦者 はたけカカシ君！
Kakashi Hatake!
What are you doing to do
for us, Kakashi?
カカシ君は
何をやってくれるのかな？
(カカシ)じゃあ 土遁の土波を。
Well, how about
the Earth Style: Mud Wave?
おぉ～ その術は
かなりチャクラがいるけど大丈夫？
Really? That jutsu requires
a considerable amount of chakra.
Are you sure about this?
フン！ 俺たちの歳で土波なんて…。
Mud Wave? At our age?
土遁 土波の術！
Earth Style! Mud Wave Jutsu!
う～ あぁ～！
文句なしの満点だ！
The judges all agree!
Perfect 10s!
優勝は はたけカカシ君！
The winner is Kakashi Hatake!
おめでとう！
ん～！
残念だったね オビト。
Too bad, Obito.
はたけ… カカシ。
Kakashi…Hatake!
遅いよ オビト！ みんな待ってるよ！
You're late, Obito!
Everyone's been waiting!
Sorry, sorry! On the way,
an old man was…
(オビト)ごめん ごめん！
途中でおじいちゃんが…。
《あっ… カカシ！》
Kakashi!
カカシも今日から仲間に入るって！
Kakashi's joining us from today!
今日は 缶蹴りやろうぜ！
Let's play kick-the-can today!
おお！ やろうぜ！
Sure! Let's play!
ハァ… ハァ…。
あとは カカシだけか。
Kakashi's the only one left.
Obito's such a fast runner.
オビトは足が速いからな。
Save us, Kakashi!
助けてくれよ カカシ！
すぐ捕まえてやる！
I'll catch him instantly!
(みんな)おぉ！
What—?!
なっ!?
仲間は絶対に助ける。
Saving my friends, no matter what…
それが俺の流儀だ！
That's my Ninja Way.
(みんな)わぁ～！
ハァハァ…。
ひえ～！
ハァ…。
ダハー！
(カカシ)なんなら鬼をかわろうか？
Want me to be "it"?
(オビト)誰が！
As if!
Obito was "it" the whole time.
ずっとオビトが鬼だったね。
でも １回も捕まらないなんて。
But he couldn't catch Kakashi,
not even once…
カカシ すっげえな！
あ 母さん！
Kakashi is amazing.
Oh, Mom!
オビト 私 帰るね。
Obito, I have to leave.
俺も。
母ちゃん！
Me too! Mom!
I won again.
また俺の勝ちだな。
でも ひとつだけ褒めてやるよ。
But I'll praise you for one thing…
今まで俺に 音を
あげなかったのは お前だけだ。
You're the only one until now
who never chickened out.
フン 偉そうに。
You show off!
Hey, I was praising you.
せっかく褒めてやってるのに。
あ 父さんだ。 じゃあな。
There's my dad! So long!
ああ またな。
Yeah… See you!
なぁ ばあちゃん 俺は
父ちゃん似かな 母ちゃん似かな。
Say, Grandma…
Am I like my dad? Or my mom?
そうだのう 両方かの。
Well, let's see…
I think both of them.
お前は 両親の
命をもらって生きとるんじゃ。
You are alive because
of your parents.
そのぶんも
他の人のために役立たねばのう。
So you must honor them both
and work for the sake of others.
うん。
やべえ やべえ やべえ！
今日だけは→
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
This is the one day I can't be late!
遅刻するわけにはいかねえんだ。
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
ハァー。
入学式から遅刻か。
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late.
そんなヤツに
アカデミーに入る資格はない。
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
無理だな。
大丈夫よ。
You'll never make it.
It's okay.
これ ちゃんと
もらっておいたから。
I got this for you.
お 俺の？
ええ。
For me?
Yes! Just submit this and
you'll be able to enroll.
この書類を出せば
問題なく入学できるって。
助かった 恩にきるぜ！
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
チッ！ 甘やかしてっと
コイツの遅刻癖 直んねえぞ。
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
うるせぇ！ やるか この！
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
なにを！
なんだよ！
Say that again!
– What?
– It's your fault!
お前が悪いんだからな。
なんだと… カカシ！
What did you say,
stupid Kakashi?
はたけカカシ。
アイツを必ず ブッ倒して→
Kakashi Hatake!
I'll take him down and become
the Hokage, no matter what!
俺は火影になる！
フフフッ その意気よ。
That's the spirit!
(みんな)ハハハハハッ！
(みんな)おお～！
すごい！
ヘヘヘッ！
Kakashi is different from us, isn't he?
やっぱりカカシは 私たちとは違うね。
バカなヤツ！ またカカシに挑んで
痛めつけられたんだって。
What a dummy!
He challenged Kakashi again
and got his butt kicked.
落ちこぼれが
トップに勝てるわけねえのに。
As if the class loser can beat
the head of the class!
(オビト)リン！
Rin?!
《俺だって
いつか写輪眼が開眼したら→
Someday, I'll awaken my Sharingan,
アイツになんて 負けねえのに…》
and I won't lose to him…
(オビト)カカシのヤツ
最近ずっと休みだな。
Kakashi hasn't been coming
to class at all lately.
(リン)なんか お父さんに
不幸があったんですって。
I heard something unfortunate
happened to his father.
(えっ…。
きっと大変なんだと思う))
I think it's a difficult time
for him right now…
(オビト)その後 お前は飛び級で
さっさとアカデミーを去っちまった。
After that, you skipped a grade
and quickly left the Academy.
あのとき 俺が お前の心にあいた
むなしさに気づいていたら→
Back then, if I had noticed
the huge emptiness in your heart…
今の運命も
少しは違っていたのかもしれない。
maybe our present destiny
might have been a little different.
俺は知らなかった。
I didn't realize how much
お前の父 サクモさんの死が→
the death of your father Sakumo
had changed you…
どれだけ
お前を変えてしまったのかを…。
Hey Rin, have you seen Kakashi lately?
Why do you ask?
さあ 皆さん
お待ちかねでございます。
I heard a rumor about him yesterday.
ざっと並んだ このメンバーでですな→
It wasn't good,
but he seemed different.
なんと 俺の歌
歌ってくれるんだってさ。
一緒に歌いたい。 皆さんも
知ってたら歌ってちょうだい。
Could it
いってみよう！
(宮本)６月５日は 北島三郎さんが
デビューした記念の日です。